# **Prabhjot Singh**

510-509-5935 | pjsingh1359@zohomail.com | Fremont, CA | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

#### SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with 1 year of experience currently building an application to aid African citizens get easier access to affordable produce and to help farmers have more ownership in their products and sales. Graduated from a 1000+ hour 6-month long intensive boot camp where I used React, Flask, SQL, and more to build 3 full stack projects.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, React Native, Next.js, Redux, JavaScript, Python, Ruby, Flask, Django, Tailwind, Git, CSS, SQL, AWS

## **PROJECTS**

FriendZone June 2023

Facebook clone where users can post and interact with others.

Live | GitHub

- Collaborative project employing contemporary development approaches like agile methodology and incorporating widely adopted tools such as React, Flask, and AWS S3 to craft a user-friendly application.
- Developed the social feed feature to closely align with Facebook's design, empowering users with the capability to create, edit, delete, and comment on posts.

Zesty July 2023

Etsy clone where users can purchase items and create listings.

Live | GitHub

- Developed secure user authentication using BCrypt hashing in Python backend with React auth routes for enhanced security.
- Engineered the database, back-end routes, and front-end layout for the application.

Tripbnb May 2023

Airbnb soft clone where users can book, review, and manage spot listings

Live | GitHub

- Employing React, Node, Express, and Sequelize, I prioritized an impeccable UI design that harnessed the
  potential of Flexbox and Grid to ensure a sleek layout.
- Enabled users to view, review, book, and manage listings through the listings page for a comprehensive user experience.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Full Stack Developer**

Aug 2023 - Present

CUBESEED AFRICA, Lagos, Nigeria

- Engineered the front and back end of the marketplace using Next.js and Django
- Aided in helping solve the problem of the rising cost of produce for citizens by creating a solution for farmers
  to have more autonomy in their product and cutting out the middleman.

### **Software Engineer Intern**

May 2022 – Feb 2023

LiveStockCity, Mount Solon, Virginia

- Collaborated with the back-end team to seamlessly integrate user sign-up, login, and social feed functionality.
- Developed features within the social feed that allow users to like and comment on posts, enhancing user engagement by 15%, and fostering a vibrant and engaging social media experience within the app.

## Amazon Warehouse Ambassador

Sep 2014 - Sep 2018

Amazon, Newark, CA

- Led a high-performing team that achieved a remarkable 10% increase in productivity through seamless and prompt delivery of customer packages.
- Exemplary collaboration with managers to efficiently process packages, supervise workers, and maintain exceptional quality standards, while promptly addressing any operational challenges or issues.

## **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Developer | Certificate Associates | Psychology App Academy – 2023 Ohlone College – 2019